Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
Guides to Special Collections in the Music Division of the Library of Congress
Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection 1878-1959 (bulk 1900-1949)
ML31.V67
Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946
Gumm, H. Harold
approximately 11,000 items 77 containers 26.0 linear feet
Music Division Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
The Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection consists of both personal and professional papers of composer and music publisher Harry Von Tilzer (1872-1946) and his brother, H. Harold Gumm (1881 or 82-1973), who was a lawyer, agent, and producer in the entertainment business. After having served as attorney for the Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co. (HVTMPC) for several decades, Harold Gumm served as executor of Harry Von Tilzer's estate and took over the company when Von Tilzer died in 1946. This collection contains the records of the HVTMPC which are inextricably combined not only with Harry Von Tilzer's papers but also with Gumm's papers and those of his firm Goldie & Gumm. Von Tilzer's personal papers include correspondence, writings, legal and financial documents, and drafts of his autobiography. The HVTMPC materials primarily consist of music (manuscript and printed), lyrics (manuscript and typewritten), scripts, legal and financial records, and a catalog of works published by HVTMPC. Most of Gumm's subject files relate to his activities as an agent for many prominent black performers of the 1930s and 1940s. Materials relating to their brothers (music publisher Will Von Tilzer; songwriter Albert Von Tilzer; and Jules and Jack Von Tilzer, who both worked in the family business) also appear in the collection. In addition, the collection contains programs, photographs, and clippings.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically therein.
People
Duke, Vernon, 1903-1969. Cabin in the sky.; Gum family.; Gumm, H. Harold--Archives.; Gumm, H. Harold--Correspondence.; Gumm, H. Harold.; Gumm, H. Harold.; Gumm, H. Harold. Von Tilzer / Gumm collection. 1878-1959.; Hairston, Jester, 1901-2000.; Hale, Teddy.; Harvey, Georgette.; Ingram, Rex, 1895-1969.; McCree, Junie, 1865-1918.; Nordstrom, Frances.; Singer, Dolph, 1900-1942.; Sterling, Andrew B., b. 1874--Correspondence.; Von Tilzer, Albert.; Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946--Archives.; Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946--Correspondence.; Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946--Photographs.; Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946.; Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946.; Von Tilzer, Harry, 1872-1946. Songs. Selections.; Von Tilzer, Jules.
Organizations
Goldie & Gumm.; Harry Von Tilzer Music Pub. Co.; Harry Von Tilzer Music Pub. Co.; Harry Von Tilzer Music Pub. Co.--Archives.
Subjects
African American entertainers.; Composers--United States--Correspondence.; Music publishers--United States.; Music publishing--United States.; Music--Manuscripts--19th century.; Music--Manuscripts--20th century.; Musical theater--United States--19th century.; Musical theater--United States--20th century.; Popular music--1901-1910.; Popular music--1911-1920.; Popular music--To 1901.; Theatrical agents--United States.; Vaudeville--United States.
Form/Genre
Clippings (Information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Legal correspondence.; Legal documents.; Photographic prints.; Programs (Documents); Scripts (Documents); Songs (Document genre)
Administrative Information
Provenance
Purchase; through the Heritage Bookshop in Los Angeles from an unidentified owner; 1982
Accruals
No further accruals are expected.
Access and Restrictions
The Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection is open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Music Division prior to visiting in order to determine whether the desired materials will be available at that time.
Certain restrictions to use or copying of materials may apply.
Biographical Note
Harry Von Tilzer was born Harold Gumm on July 8, 1872 to Jacob and Sarah Tilzer Gumm in Goshen, Indiana. At the age of fourteen he ran away to join the circus, and at seventeen joined the Chamberlain Stock Company in Chicago, changing his name from Gumm to a variant of his mother's maiden name, Von Tilzer. He moved to New York in 1892, and was a performer on the vaudeville circuit for many years, frequently partnered with George Sidney and managed by Tony Pastor. In conjunction with his vaudeville performing, he had been writing songs, and in New York began to peddle them in Tin Pan Alley -- a slang term for the music-publishing district that has been credited to Von Tilzer himself. He joined the publishing firm of Shapiro, Bernstein in 1899, but soon left to form his own firm, the Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co. (HVTMPC), in 1902.
In his unpublished biography (many drafts of which are found in this collection), Von Tilzer claims to have written over 8000 songs during his career, of which 2000 were published, some of the best known being "A Bird in a Gilded Cage" (1900), "In the Sweet Bye and Bye" (1902), "The Cubanola Glide" (1909), and "That Old Irish Mother of Mine" (1920). In addition, he wrote the music for and financed the production of a number of musicals, including The Fisher Maiden (1903), Heigh Ho (1905), and The Kissing Girl (1909). In addition to writing and publishing songs, Von Tilzer was active in establishing organizations such as the Song Writers' Protective Association, and, as an early and active member of the American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers (ASCAP), joined with composers such as Irving Berlin, Jerome Kern, Victor Herbert and John Philip Sousa in attempting to effect changes in the music copyright laws.
Harry Von Tilzer had several brothers, most of whom also took the name Von Tilzer: Will Von Tilzer, a music publisher in his own right who was president of the Broadway Music Corporation; Albert Von Tilzer, a songwriter who settled in California and is best known for songs such as "Take Me Out to the Ball Game;" Jules Von Tilzer, who worked with his brother Harry at the HVTMPC; and Jack Von Tilzer, who also worked for a time in the family business. Only H. Harold Gumm retained the family name, and started the firm of Goldie & Gumm with partner William V. Goldie. Trained as a lawyer, Gumm was active on both the East and West Coasts as a theatrical agent and attorney who had as clients some of the best known black performers of the 1930s and 1940s.
The firm of Goldie & Gumm also handled the legal affairs of the Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co. up to and following Harry's death in January of 1946. At that point, Harold Gumm, executor of Von Tilzer's estate, took over as the president of the publishing company. Partner William Goldie continued to handle the firm's legal matters from that point, but Gumm's activities as a theatrical agent were largely curtailed. Extensive litigation over the HVTMPC catalog dragged through the 1940s and 1950s, and the catalog was put up for sale in 1957.
Scope and Content Note
The Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection consists of both personal and professional papers of composer and music publisher Harry Von Tilzer and his brother, H. Harold Gumm, who was both a lawyer and an agent cum producer in the entertainment business. The date span of the collection is from 1878 to 1959, with the bulk of the materials dating between the early 1900s and the 1940s. Because Harold Gumm served as executor of Harry Von Tilzer's estate and took over the Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co. when Von Tilzer died in 1946 (after having served as attorney for the publishing house for several decades), the records of the HVTMPC are inextricably combined not only with Harry Von Tilzer's papers but also with Gumm's papers and those of Goldie & Gumm. Various papers of Harry's other brothers also appear in the collection. Therefore, although the collection has been organized into traditional series according to type of materials, within each series type the materials are divided into the following categories by originator (where necessary): Harry Von Tilzer, Estate of Harry Von Tilzer, Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co., [Other Von Tilzer brothers], H. Harold Gumm, William V. Goldie, and Goldie & Gumm.
The personal papers of Harry Von Tilzer consist of writings, correspondence, and various legal and financial documents. There are several manuscript and typewritten drafts of his unpublished autobiography, which chronicles not only his own experiences as a vaudevillian and composer but also the development of the music publishing business in New York from the turn of the century through the 1930s. Noteworthy in his correspondence is that with one of his primary collaborators, lyricist Andrew B. Sterling. His legal papers include song contracts with other publishers, including those dating from before he established his own publishing house in 1902. The records of his estate, both legal and financial, provide additional insight into his personal and family ties, particularly his relationship with his stepdaughter, Aimee V. Samuels.
The materials in the collection from the records of the Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co. consist primarily of music, lyrics, scripts, and legal and financial records. There is a significant amount of songs, with over 800 titles in manuscript form, ranging from lead sheets without words to complete piano-vocal scores. There are an additional five boxes of lyric sheets, both manuscript and typewritten, some of which designate the letter names of notes over the words to indicate the intended melody. An ASCAP listing of the HVTMPC catalog, revised in 1957, provides the most recent itemization of the publisher's list (see box 69).
Several musicals are represented in the collection, including orchestral scores and parts for The Kissing Girl, The Fisher Maiden, and Tiddleywinks (or Snowdrop and the Pirates). There are four boxes of scripts without music as well, representing authors such as Dolph Singer, Frances Nordstrom, and Junie McCree. A number of untitled "gags" and "specials" in manuscript form are also included.
The financial records of the HVTMPC are far from complete, including ledgers, financial reports, ASCAP royalty distributions and the like but covering only limited and erratic date spans. The legal files of the HVTMPC are far more substantial, particularly in the contracts and litigation files. There are more than 120 song contracts in the collection, as well as numerous other contracts with authors and producers. The litigation files are highlighted by the papers of HVTMPC vs. Jerry Vogel Music Co. et al and its appeal, the correspondence, depositions, and other trial documents of which fill four boxes and span the years 1937 to 1955.
The subject files and correspondence are among the most noteworthy of H. Harold Gumm's papers. Most of Gumm's subject files consist of the correspondence, programs, financial records, and/or clippings relating to his activities as an agent for black performers such as Georgette Harvey, Jester Hairston, Rex Ingram, and Teddy Hale. Another file documents Gumm's participation in a touring production of Cabin in the Sky, originating in Chicago and starring Ethel Waters, Todd Duncan, and Rex Ingram. Gumm's correspondence with Walter Meyers, a Hollywood agent, and William Redford, Gumm's California representative, document Gumm's activities as an agent and producer involved in stage, film, and ultimately television productions.
The photographs in the collection include not only numerous professional and personal shots of Harry Von Tilzer and his brothers but also many photographs of early vaudeville performers, some of which bear inscriptions to Harry or Albert Von Tilzer. Other series include an assortment of programs from music halls and vaudeville houses dating from 1906 to 1940 and a large number of clippings from the late 1800s to the 1950s.
Claudia Widgery, September 1993
Organization of the Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection
The Von Tilzer / Gumm Collection is organized into 13 series:
Biographical Materials
Writings
Correspondence
Music
Scripts
Subject Files
Legal Papers
Financial Papers
Catalog of the Harry Von Tilzer Music Publishing Co.
Programs
Photographs
Clippings
Miscellany
http://lccn.loc.gov/2006568222
Container List
- Biographical Materials (Box 1)
  This series contains manuscript and typewritten materials, mostly undated; biographical summaries and press releases; lists of songs and musicals by the Von Tilzers; transcripts of interviews with Harry Von Tilzer; typescripts of articles about Harry Von Tilzer; miscellaneous.
  - Biographical data (typewritten biographical summaries, press release, etc.) (Box-folder 1/1)
  - List of biographical data (for California) [citations of clippings about Harry Von Tilzer] (Box-folder 1/2)
  - List of songs by Harry Von Tilzer (Box-folder 1/3)
  - List of songs by Albert Von Tilzer (Box-folder 1/4)
  - List of musicals by Albert Von Tilzer (Box-folder 1/5)
  - List of songs - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 1/6)
  - The Story behind the Song [descriptions of songs by Harry Von Tilzer] (Box-folder 1/7)
  - Transcripts of interviews with Harry Von Tilzer, 1939 and undated, (2 folders) (Box-folder 1/8-9)
  - "Harry and Albert Von Tilzer" [typescript of article for Billboard, March 19, 19--] (Box-folder 1/10)
  - "3000 Songs Before His First Real Hit" [typescript of article for Cosmopolitan, July 1926] (Box-folder 1/11)
  - Membership cards of Harry Von Tilzer (Box-folder 1/12)
- Writings (Box 1-2)
  This series contains manuscript and typescript items, mostly undated; Harry Von Tilzer's autobiography (several versions); and writings by others regarding Harry Von Tilzer's autobiography, such as synopses, screen treatments, and comments.
  - Writings by Harry Von Tilzer
    - Mister Tin Pan Alley, Himself, Typescript, 164 p., with cover letter from Harry Von Tilzer to H. Harold Gumm; Typescript, 164 p.; Typescript, 159 p. (complete) (Box-folder 1/13-15)
    - Story of Harry Von Tilzer's Career, Typescript, 194 p. (Box-folder 1/16)
    - Story of Harry Von Tilzer's Career, Typescript, partial, 23 p. (Box-folder 1/17)
    - [Untitled autobiography], Holograph manuscript, pencil on oversize brown paper, 65 p. (Box-folder OV 1)
    - [Untitled autobiography], Typescript, 158 p. (Box-folder 1/18)
    - Writing a Popular Song, Holograph manuscript, 5 p. (Box-folder 1/19)
  - Writings by Others
    - Culver, Lillian. Synopsis of Mister Tin Pan Alley, Himself (Box-folder 2/1)
    - Herzig, Sig, and Albert Lewis. Take Me Back to New York Town [treatment of the Von Tilzer Story, 1949] (Box-folder 2/2)
    - Shaw, E. A. Synopsis of Mister Tin Pan Alley, Himself (Box-folder 2/3)
    - The Von Tilzers: Skeleton Synopsis of Mister Tin Pan Alley, Himself (Box-folder 2/4)
    - Suggested Screen Treatment of the Von Tilzers (Box-folder 2/5)
    - H. Harold Gumm's comments on the life story of Harry Von Tilzer (Box-folder 2/6)
- Correspondence, 1921-1958 (Box 2-10)
  This series contains correspondence sent and received by Harry Von Tilzer (boxes 2-4), H. Harold Gumm (boxes 5-10), and William V. Goldie & others (box 10).
  Arranged alphabetically by correspondent, with the office correspondence of H. Harold Gumm arranged chronologically by year.
  - Harry Von Tilzer
    - Adams, Robert W. (Box-folder 2/7)
    - American Red Cross (Box-folder 2/8)
    - Anheuser-Busch, inc. (Box-folder 2/9)
    - D. Appleton-Century Company (Box-folder 2/10)
    - A.S.C.A.P. (Box-folder 2/11)
    - Ash, Paul (Box-folder 2/12)
    - Aucoin, Lionel A. (Box-folder 2/13)
    - Authors League of America (Box-folder 2/14)
    - Aylward, James P. (Box-folder 2/15)
    - Baer, Arthur "Bugs" (Box-folder 2/16)
    - Bellos, George (Box-folder 2/17)
    - Irving Berlin, Inc. (Box-folder 2/18)
    - Bernard, Sam (Box-folder 2/19)
    - Bird, Carol (Box-folder 2/20)
    - Brahany, Thomas (Box-folder 2/21)
    - Bryan, Vincent (Box-folder 2/22)
    - Bye, George T. (Box-folder 2/23)
    - Capital Music Co. (Box-folder 2/24)
    - Cerf, Bennett (Box-folder 2/25)
    - Cochrane, Nick (Box-folder 2/26)
    - Cohan, George M. (Box-folder 2/27)
    - Conn, Dick (Box-folder 2/28)
    - Cooper, Charles G. (Box-folder 2/29)
    - Costello, Harry F. (Box-folder 2/30)
    - Curtis, Billy (Box-folder 2/31)
    - Davis, Clare B. (Box-folder 2/32)
    - Decca Records, Inc. (Box-folder 2/33)
    - Diamond, Louis S. (Box-folder 2/34)
    - Dillon, William A. (Box-folder 2/35)
    - Dreyfus, Max (Box-folder 2/36)
    - Durling, E. V. (Box-folder 2/37)
    - Edwards, Leo (Box-folder 2/38)
    - Federal Trade Commission (Box-folder 2/39)
    - Feist, Leo (Box-folder 2/40)
    - Fox, Harry (Box-folder 2/41)
    - Francis, Day & Hunter (Box-folder 2/42)
    - Goldie, William V. (Box-folder 2/43)
    - Green, Abel (Box-folder 2/44)
    - Grosvenor Library (Box-folder 2/45)
    - Gumm, H. Harold (Box-folder 3/1)
    - Harmon, Roy (Box-folder 3/2)
    - Healy, Vincent (Box-folder 3/3)
    - Hill, Gus (Box-folder 3/4)
    - Hueston, Billy (Box-folder 3/5)
    - Indiana University (Box-folder 3/6)
    - Jones, Francis Arthur (Box-folder 3/7)
    - Kenny, Nick (Box-folder 3/8)
    - Kerr, Harry D. (Box-folder 3/9)
    - Kings Feature Syndicate (Box-folder 3/10)
    - Lang, Helen (Box-folder 3/11)
    - Levish, Thomas (Box-folder 3/12)
    - Lewis, Ted (Mrs.) (Box-folder 3/13)
    - Lucas, Jimmie (Box-folder 3/14)
    - Maddock, C. B. (Box-folder 3/15)
    - Martin, Hunter (Box-folder 3/16)
    - McKeon, Joseph H. (Box-folder 3/17)
    - Moran, Edward P. (Box-folder 3/18)
    - Munters, Saul L. (Box-folder 3/19)
    - Murphy, E. H. (Box-folder 3/20)
    - Murphy, Mrs. Stanley (Elizabeth M.) (Box-folder 3/21)
    - Music Dealers Service (Box-folder 3/22)
    - Music Publishers' Holding Corp. (Box-folder 3/23)
    - Music Publishers' Protective Association (Box-folder 3/24)
    - National Variety Artists (Box-folder 3/25)
    - Newman, Alfred (Box-folder 3/26)
    - Nizer, Louis (Box-folder 3/27)
    - O'Brien, A. H. (Box-folder 3/28)
    - Peer, Ralph (Box-folder 3/29)
    - Platzman, Eugene (Box-folder 3/30)
    - Powell, W. Templar (Box-folder 3/31)
    - Progressive Music Publishers (Box-folder 3/32)
    - Ringle, Dave (Box-folder 3/33)
    - The Rotarian (Box-folder 3/34)
    - Ruby, Harry (Box-folder 3/35)
    - Salkow, Irving (Box-folder 3/36)
    - Samuels, Aimee V. (Box-folder 3/37)
    - Seamon, Harry (Box-folder 3/38)
    - Segool, Benjamin (Box-folder 3/39)
    - Shapiro, Elliot (Box-folder 3/40)
    - Singer, Dolph (Box-folder 3/41)
    - Smith, Robert Garland (Box-folder 3/42)
    - Snyder, Ted (Box-folder 3/43)
    - Song Writers' Protective Association (Box-folder 3/44)
    - Spaeth, Sigmund (Box-folder 3/45)
    - Sterling, Andrew B., (4 folders) (Box-folder 4/1-4)
    - Tamarin, Al (Box-folder 4/5)
    - Theatre Guild, Inc. (Box-folder 4/6)
    - Tucker, Sophie (Box-folder 4/7)
    - USO Camp Shows, Inc. (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Vestal, A. H. (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Von Tilzer, Karlyn (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Von Tilzer, William (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Ward, Kathrin Clare (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Wattenberg, A. M. (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Whipple, Odell (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Whiting, Sadie (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Winchell, Walter (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 4/17)
  - Jules Von Tilzer
    - Albertina, Ethel (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Burton, Jack (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Campbell, S. Brunson (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Ferguson, Dave (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Goldie, William V. (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Hynard, Marjorie (Box-folder 4/23)
    - Jewish Theatrical Guild of America (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Johnson, Irbie (Box-folder 4/25)
    - Kendis, Lillian (Mrs. James) (Box-folder 4/26)
    - Radcliffe, Ella (Box-folder 4/27)
    - Saltpeter, Sophie (Box-folder 4/28)
    - Salvador & Nigro (Box-folder 4/29)
    - Shapiro, Elliot (Box-folder 4/30)
    - Sontag, Sophie (Box-folder 4/31)
    - Sterling, Andrew B. (Box-folder 4/32)
    - Terker, Arthur (Box-folder 4/33)
    - Von Tilzer, Albert (Box-folder 4/34)
    - Steven Wise Free Synagogue (Box-folder 4/35)
    - Miscellaneous, (2 folders) (Box-folder 4/36-37)
    - re: HVTMPC payments (Box-folder 4/38)
  - H. Harold Gumm
    - Arnow, Max, (3 folders) (Box-folder 5/1-3)
    - A.S.C.A.P., (4 folders) (Box-folder 5/4-6)
    - Beale, Ella (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Benjamin, Ben (Box-folder 5/8)
    - Bernstein, Harry M. (Box-folder 5/9)
    - Blau, Victor (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Blumberg, Nate J. (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Blume & Jolles (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Blume, Jolles, Gruber, Szabad & Gerson (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Borinstein, Manuel R. (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Bornstein, Saul (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Brandon, Joseph M. (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Broadway Muisc Corp. (Box-folder 6/2)
    - Bryk, Hugo (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Davis, Irving K. (Box-folder 6/4)
    - DeMarco, Tony & Sally (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Douglass, John W. (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Dreyer, Louis A. (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Finkelstein, Jake R. (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Fitzgerald, Leo (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Fox, Harry (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Foyer, Bernie (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Garfunkel, George (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Gilbert, L. Wolfe (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Gleis, Stanley N. (Box-folder 6/14)
    - Goldberg, Jack (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Goldie, William V. (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Greer, Norman & Gloria (Box-folder 6/17)
    - Gumm, Elizabeth (Box-folder 6/18)
    - Gumm, Trudy (Mrs. H. Harold) (Box-folder 6/19)
    - Hennigs, Frank (Box-folder 6/20)
    - Higgins, Joe & Sadie (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Hirsch & Co. (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Kepler, Tobias A. (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Klausner, Bertha (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Landers, Rolli (Mrs. Lou) (Box-folder 6/25)
    - Leibner, Sol L. (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Lewis, Albert (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Lewis, Ted & Adah (Box-folder 6/28)
    - Library of Congress (Box-folder 6/29)
    - McEathron, Margaret (Mrs. C. N) (Box-folder 7/1)
    - McLaughlin, Edward J. (Box-folder 7/2)
    - McPherson, Harry (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Metropolitan Life Insurance (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Meyers, Abe (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Meyers, Walter, (3 folders) (Box-folder 7/6-8)
    - Miller, Taps (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Mitchell, Mae (Box-folder 7/10)
    - Moran, Edward (Box-folder 7/11)
    - Leo Morrison, Inc. (Box-folder 7/12)
    - New York Times Sunday Magazine (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Orsatti Agency (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Page, Olivia (Box-folder 7/15)
    - Paul, Robert T. (Box-folder 7/16)
    - Radio Station KNX (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Redford, William, (2 folders) (Box-folder 7/18-19)
    - Reinhardt, Max (Box-folder 7/20)
    - Romberg, Sigmund (Box-folder 7/21)
    - Salkow, Irving (Box-folder 7/22)
    - Saltpeter, Sophie (Box-folder 7/23)
    - Singer, Wally (Mrs. Leo) (Box-folder 7/24)
    - Smitman, Ralph (Box-folder 7/25)
    - Sontag, Mae (Box-folder 7/26)
    - Spaeth, Sigmund (Box-folder 7/27)
    - Starn, E. A (HVTMPC, 1921-1922) (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Sterling, Andrew B. (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Sullivan, Ed & Sylvia (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Thomas, Earl G. (Box-folder 8/4)
    - U. S. Treasury Dept. (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Von Tilzer, Albert (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Von Tilzer, Jules (Box-folder 8/7)
    - Von Tilzer, Will & Blanche (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Wing, Ted & Patricia (Box-folder 8/9)
    - Winkler, Daniel M. (Box-folder 8/10)
    - Albert Woodley Co. (Box-folder 8/11)
    - re: Harry Von Tilzer Memorial Tribute, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 8/12)
    - Negotiations re: Sale of HVTMPC in 1957 (Box-folder 8/13)
    - Office correspondence, 1946-1958, from the files of H. Harold Gumm, (7 folders) (Box-folder 9/1-7)
    - Miscellaneous correspondence from the files of H. Harold Gumm (by subject):
      - Automobile (Box-folder 10/1)